<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TEJI</title>
    <description>TEJI RSS</description>
    <link>https://teji.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://teji.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>


<item>
  <title>The Information Diet</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/infodiet</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/infodiet</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>The Information Diet</h1>

    <p>
      Thoughts on mindful consumption online written by Jet Williams on Jan
      15th, 2024
    </p>

    <p>
      Over the past decade our attention spans have been shattered and we can no
      longer focus on anything for more than five minutes, before getting bored
      and moving on to the next thing. The introduction of short form content
      over the past decade has only compounded the effects mass consumption of
      media has had on our attention spans
    </p>

    <p>
      A decade from now I believe we will look back on this era of Internet
      consumption the same way we look back on our grand parents who thought
      smoking was harmless. In hindsight it's going to be obvious — anything in
      excess is going to have harmful effects in some way on us.
    </p>

    <p>
      Which is why I believe we should become more mindful of our consumption
      online. One way to do this is to introduce an information diet into our
      online routines. Much like a traditional diet we need to limit the amount
      of junk we consume and make a conscious effort to eat foods rich in
      nutrition.
    </p>

    <p>
      We can start this process by simply pruning what we don't need online.
      This can be done by first unfollowing all of the accounts you really don't
      care about. This should reduce your feed to those that truely matter in
      your lives.
    </p>

    <p>
      However, there's an issue with this because todays algorithms focus less
      on your network of friends and accounts you follow and more on content the
      algorithm thinks you might like. So even if you followed five people you
      will still have an endless amount of content you can scroll through.
    </p>

    <p>
      One solution to this is building your own highly curated feed of content
      using an old technology called RSS, which stands for really simple
      syndication. There are hundreds of videos and tutorials online explaining
      how to setup your own RSS feed using one of the many RSS readers you can
      download on your device.
    </p>

    <p>
      In short, the way RSS works is you copy the RSS feed link from any source
      of content you find interesting and plug it into your RSS reader which
      will continually check if any of your feeds have added new content.
    </p>

    <p>
      Keep in mind, I'm not advocating to cut the algorithm completely out of
      our lives. It's a fantastic tool that can be used as a place of discovery.
      However, if we are not careful we can quickly become a slave to them. Your
      attention is a muscle that should be trained and it's something I
      personally want to improve in my life.
    </p>

    <p>
      I've found that reading long form articles and books from credible sources
      who aren't trying to play into the algorithm can often be a fantastic way
      to improve your focus. I'd recommend a set of people for you to read but
      what we deem useful is often relative to the individual. You could also
      physically limit access to your devices by placing them in different
      rooms, if you really want to complete a certain task and need a
      distraction free environment.
    </p>

    <p>
      In summary, It's not necessarily about what you consume but it's about
      becoming more mindful of our consumption patterns. The answer is often the
      one you don't want to hear and it's the fact that to improve focus we need
      to do hard things. So the next time you think about picking up a your
      phone to scroll on TikTok how about you try read a chapter or two of that
      book you've been meaning to read.
    </p>

    <p>
      This essay was inspired by Mark Mansons video titled:
      <a href="https://youtu.be/QllKrUi_fy4?si=JxuwcV3zoQXOg-hD"
        >The Attention Diet: Be More Focused</a
      >
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>


  ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Letting Go</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/letgo</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/letgo</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
    <h1>Letting Go</h1>

    <p>Thoughts on letting go written by Jet Williams on Jan 11th, 2024</p>

    <p>
      The Universe is a funny place. It often feels like everything you want you
      can’t have. It’s this desperation and neediness for things to work out
      that often repels the desired outcome far away from you.
    </p>

    <p>
      I’ve experienced this first hand in my life when it comes to becoming a
      full time creator. I dropped everything to focus on my passion and build
      things online. Yet when the neediness for things to work came in as
      financial pressures began to grow — I started catering my ideas to the
      algorithm and what I should make instead of what I wanted to make.
    </p>

    <p>
      It’s the age old conundrum where the musician who started off making songs
      in their bedroom signs a record deal and is now expected to start putting
      out an album each and every year. As time goes on they lose motivation as
      the label pushes for certain kinds of songs to be made over the
      experimental works that got them to where they are in the first place.
    </p>

    <p>
      In some ways it feels like we are abusing our creativity when we look to
      profit from it. I'm in no way saying you’re not allowed to make money from
      your art — but I am thinking we may need to become more mindful of how we
      treat our creativity.
    </p>

    <p>
      Perhaps instead of needing our creativity to work we just let go and allow
      it to work. It’s something I’ve been working on that has been extremely
      hard for myself. I’ve decided go against all advice from the online gurus
      who tell you to ‘burn the boats’ and ‘go all in’ if you want it to work in
      favour of now going out and looking for a job that will provide enough
      stability to reduce the amount of pressure I’m putting on my creativity.
    </p>

    <p>
      I’m a strong believer in the <strong>law of detachment</strong> which is a
      belief that
      <strong
        >you can have anything you want as long as you don't need it</strong
      >. I’ve found this principle to apply to all areas of life —
      <strong>neediness repels and abundance attracts</strong>.
    </p>

    <p>
      Today I let go of all pressures I’ve put on myself and release the immense
      build up of worry and anxiety in my life in favour of acceptance and
      learning to go with the flow of life.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>


  ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Productivity</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/productivity</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/productivity</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
         <h1>Productivity</h1>

    <p>Thoughts on productivity written by Jet Williams on Jan 11th, 2024</p>

    <p>
      I wrote this list as a basic framework to help increase the productivity
      in my life. These principles are merely guidelines and the opposite of
      each idea is almost also true in some cases.
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>Eat the frog first</li>
      <li>Accept that everything is a work in progress</li>
      <li>Get going then get good</li>
      <li>Brick by brick</li>
      <li>Laugh at perfection</li>
      <li>Finished work creates more finished work</li>
      <li>Fail more but learn from your mistakes</li>
      <li>Write to organise your thoughts and ideas</li>
      <li>Allocate time dedicated to thinking about ideas</li>
      <li>Write lots of lists</li>
      <li>If you get an idea write it down immediately</li>
      <li>Start what you finish but also know when to quit</li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Some ideas in my list that have been adapted from this
      <a href="https://youtu.be/bJQj1uKtnus?si=d-ahQSZlAYYy4x5n"
        >YouTube video</a
      >, <a href="https://sigilwen.ca/productivity.html">Sigil Wen</a> and
      <a href="https://blog.samaltman.com/productivity">Sam Altman</a>.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>

  ]]></description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>We Need Each Other</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/eachother</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/eachother</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
         <h1>We Need Each Other</h1>

    <p>Written by Jet Williams on Jan 10th, 2024</p>

    <p>
      The iPhone may be designed in California but it's the perfect example of
      what we can build when we work together. It may be hard to see the
      interconnectedness of all things until you look under the screen and
      realise that all the raw materials and components that make up the iPhone
      come from all over the planet — There's chips being made in Taiwan that
      are then shipped to Japan for assembly, while there's also miners in Chile
      digging for the copper that's used to create the wires that line your
      phone.
    </p>

    <p>
      You can break down the chain of assembly of literally anything — ideas,
      shoes, novels, songs and even YOU can be broken down into a long line of
      inputs. Something I've said for years is '<i
        >everything is a remix of a remix</i
      >' and I believe we should become more aware of how influenced we are from
      the world around us. All of your ideas and opinions are a mashup of the
      inputs you've received over your lifetime.
    </p>

    <p>
      My own personal taste in clothes, music, movies etc. all comes from my
      experience growing up and being surrounded by both my mother and fathers
      interests. I probably wouldn't be designing clothes if I didn't have to
      help my Mum take photos of her own clothes for her eBay store. Perhaps, I
      also wouldn't be off on crazy adventures around the world if I didn't grow
      up playing my Dad's favourite video game Tomb Raider.
    </p>

    <p>
      There's a
      <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DcWqzZ3I2cY">great interview</a>
      between Lex Fridman and Jeff Bezos where Bezos goes into detail explaining
      how he would've never been able to build Amazon if it weren't for
      pre-existing infrastructure. Without things like credit cards and the
      postal service Amazon would've never existed. He's now making it a
      priority to build the next wave of infrastructure for the next generation
      to iterate upon what he's managed to build.
    </p>

    <p>
      Everything you see in this world is apart of a universal interconnected
      web of ideas, things and people. To think it's possible to go at this
      alone is ludicrous — countries need each other, couples need each other,
      friends need each other, companies need each other,
      <strong>we need each other.</strong>
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>

  ]]></description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Sunsets and Rainbows</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/rainbows</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/rainbows</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 9 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>Sunsets and Rainbows</h1>

    <p>Written by Jet Williams on Jan 9th, 2024</p>

    <p>
      Yesterday, I saw a full rainbow and it was a good reminder of how beauty
      often appears after the storm clears. For the past six months I’ve been
      dealing with one of the biggest personal challenges I’ve faced in my life
      yet. However, I’m a huge believer in reframing any circumstance you find
      yourself in.
    </p>

    <p>
      I used to be an avid photographer and one of the key understandings I
      learnt during my time taking thousands of photos is — If you ever wanted
      to get good lighting or a beautiful sunset you had to have the right
      weather conditions.
    </p>

    <p>
      Now what are the right weather conditions? If it’s a clear day without a
      cloud in the sky you’ll often get a mediocre sunset. Sure it will look
      alright but it’s not going to be one of those sunsets everyone on your
      Instagram posts a story of.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you want a real sunset - you’re going to need some rain and clouds. It
      sounds counter intuitive wishing for poor weather when you want to catch a
      beautiful sunset, but it’s the only way to produce an exceptional result.
    </p>

    <p>
      Back in the day my friend
      <a href="https://instagram.com/moistmark">Mark</a>, another talented
      photographer and I would often drive for multiple hours through wet
      weather in hopes of catching the ever elusive magical sunset. Most of the
      time our journeys would lead to nothing but for a small fraction of our
      trips the conditions would line up perfectly and we’d spend the entire
      evening chasing the light.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you want a mediocre sunset (or life that is) wish for clear skies.
      However, if you want to live an exceptional life full of vibrant colors —
      you need to be okay with a few rainy days. A key takeaway here is
      understanding that not every rainy day is going to lead to a magnificent
      sunset and you need to be okay with that. However, a day may come when
      things are looking their worst and you are soaking wet until suddenly you
      look up.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>

  ]]></description>
</item>



    <item>
  <title>TEJI's Principles for Life</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/principles</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/principles</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 3 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>Principles</h1>

    <p>
      A list of guiding principles for life by Jet Williams on Jan 3rd, 2023
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Use what you have</li>
      <li>Never hold in a compliment</li>
      <li>Stay curious</li>
      <li>Challenge yourself</li>
      <li>Listen more than you talk</li>
      <li>Embrace the unknown</li>
      <li>Think for yourself</li>
      <li>Don't be afraid to ask for help</li>
      <li>Good habits are contagious</li>
      <li>Learn to let go of things</li>
      <li>Don't forget to play</li>
      <li>Progress over perfection</li>
      <li>Stand up for yourself</li>
      <li>Tell the truth</li>
      <li>Talk to strangers</li>
      <li>How you react is everything</li>
      <li>Accept your emotions</li>
      <li>Know when to roll up your sleeves</li>
      <li>Know when to rest</li>
      <li>Always be creating</li>
      <li>Pessimism is a virus</li>
      <li>Keep your word</li>
      <li>Believe</li>
      <li>Loss and gain are the same</li>
      <li>Life is in the grey</li>
      <li>Say what you mean</li>
      <li>Avoid gossip</li>
      <li>Know when to break the rules</li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      NOTE: Principles shouldn't always be followed. There is always an
      exception. Know when to break the rules.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>
  ]]></description>
</item>

    <!-- More <item> elements here for additional posts -->

  </channel>
</rss>