<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TEJI</title>
    <description>TEJI RSS</description>
    <link>https://teji.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://teji.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>



<item>
  <title>Sunsets and Rainbows</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/rainbows</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/rainbows</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 9 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>Sunsets and Rainbows</h1>

    <p>Written by Jet Williams on Jan 9th, 2024</p>

    <p>
      Yesterday, I saw a full rainbow and it was a good reminder of how beauty
      often appears after the storm clears. For the past six months I’ve been
      dealing with one of the biggest personal challenges I’ve faced in my life
      yet. However, I’m a huge believer in reframing any circumstance you find
      yourself in.
    </p>

    <p>
      I used to be an avid photographer and one of the key understandings I
      learnt during my time taking thousands of photos is — If you ever wanted
      to get good lighting or a beautiful sunset you had to have the right
      weather conditions.
    </p>

    <p>
      Now what are the right weather conditions? If it’s a clear day without a
      cloud in the sky you’ll often get a mediocre sunset. Sure it will look
      alright but it’s not going to be one of those sunsets everyone on your
      Instagram posts a story of.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you want a real sunset - you’re going to need some rain and clouds. It
      sounds counter intuitive wishing for poor weather when you want to catch a
      beautiful sunset, but it’s the only way to produce an exceptional result.
    </p>

    <p>
      Back in the day my friend
      <a href="https://instagram.com/moistmark">Mark</a>, another talented
      photographer and I would often drive for multiple hours through wet
      weather in hopes of catching the ever elusive magical sunset. Most of the
      time our journeys would lead to nothing but for a small fraction of our
      trips the conditions would line up perfectly and we’d spend the entire
      evening chasing the light.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you want a mediocre sunset (or life that is) wish for clear skies.
      However, if you want to live an exceptional life full of vibrant colors —
      you need to be okay with a few rainy days. A key takeaway here is
      understanding that not every rainy day is going to lead to a magnificent
      sunset and you need to be okay with that. However, a day may come when
      things are looking their worst and you are soaking wet until suddenly you
      look up.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>

  ]]></description>
</item>



    <item>
  <title>TEJI's Principles for Life</title>
  <link>https://teji.io/library/essays/principles</link>
  <guid>https://teji.io/library/essays/principles</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 3 Jan 2024 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>jet@teji.io (Jet)</author>
  <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>Principles</h1>

    <p>
      A list of guiding principles for life by Jet Williams on Jan 3rd, 2023
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Use what you have</li>
      <li>Never hold in a compliment</li>
      <li>Stay curious</li>
      <li>Challenge yourself</li>
      <li>Listen more than you talk</li>
      <li>Embrace the unknown</li>
      <li>Think for yourself</li>
      <li>Don't be afraid to ask for help</li>
      <li>Good habits are contagious</li>
      <li>Learn to let go of things</li>
      <li>Don't forget to play</li>
      <li>Progress over perfection</li>
      <li>Stand up for yourself</li>
      <li>Tell the truth</li>
      <li>Talk to strangers</li>
      <li>How you react is everything</li>
      <li>Accept your emotions</li>
      <li>Know when to roll up your sleeves</li>
      <li>Know when to rest</li>
      <li>Always be creating</li>
      <li>Pessimism is a virus</li>
      <li>Keep your word</li>
      <li>Believe</li>
      <li>Loss and gain are the same</li>
      <li>Life is in the grey</li>
      <li>Say what you mean</li>
      <li>Avoid gossip</li>
      <li>Know when to break the rules</li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      NOTE: Principles shouldn't always be followed. There is always an
      exception. Know when to break the rules.
    </p>

    <h3>
      <a href="https://teji.io/index.html">Home</a>
    </h3>
  ]]></description>
</item>

    <!-- More <item> elements here for additional posts -->

  </channel>
</rss>